# Rinat Abdrashitov

rinat.abdras@gmail.com | +1-647-295-1387 | Toronto, ON, Canada www.dgp.toronto.edu/~rinat | github.com/rin-23

## **ABOUT**

Computer graphics engineer and researcher with over two years experience working in industry and publications in top graphics venues. Experienced in designing and implementing algorithms for solving **geometry** processing problems as well as strong **C++** and **3D graphics** programming skills.

## **EDUCATION**

# **University of Toronto**

Ph.D. candidate, Computer Science

Master of Science, Computer Science

Honors Bachelor of Computer Science with Distinction

Toronto, Canada 01/2016 – 04/2021 (expected) 09/2013 – 01/2015 09/2008 – 06/2012

## **EXPERIENCE**

SideFX Software

Toronto, Canada

Research Engineer

intern 05/2019 – 02/2020, part-time 02/2020 - current

- Designed and implemented a non-rigid surface registration algorithm to deform mesh templates to fit partial, incomplete, and noisy 3D mesh scans.
- Wrote a production-quality nonlinear least squares solver, using C++ and Eigen, for the core optimization problem, while ensuring speed, robustness, and numerical accuracy.
- Implemented the results of the work using C++ and Python and integrated it into Houdini 18.5 (TopoTransfer Node) which is an industry-standard software used in film, TV, and video games.

# **University of Toronto**

Toronto, Canada

*Ph.D. Student* (Advisor: Professor Karan Singh)

01/2016 - 04/2021 (expected)

- Performed research in novel interactive techniques for 3D modeling, face animation, and fabrication.
- Solved complex geometry problems on triangular meshes like segmentation, smoothing, deformation, reconstruction and gained experience in applying linear algebra and numerical optimization to solve math computational problems.
- Used C++ and OpenGL to develop interactive research prototypes.
- Results were published at the top computer graphics and HCI conferences (see publications).

#### Conceptualiz Inc.

Toronto, Canada 02/2015 – 01/2016

Research Engineer

- Built an iPad application from the ground up that allows orthopedic surgeons to perform pre-operative planning in a 3D environment using patient-specific CT scan data.
- Developed a custom real-time rendering engine, using OpenGL ES, GLSL, and C++, to render high-resolution polygonal models of bone tissue on a mobile GPU.
- Gained experience with software design patterns while developing a set of interactive tools for creating implant models to reflect the workflow of orthopedic surgeons.
- The app was successfully released on the App Store under the name of Ossa3D and it's the first app of its kind available on tablet devices.

# **XtremeLabs Inc.** (acquired by Pivotal Software Inc.)

Software Developer

Toronto, Canada 09/2012 – 09/2013

- Developed high profile iOS applications starting from the concept to submitting the finished product to the App Store. Clients included Bell, Mountain Equipment Co-op, and The Globe and Mail.
- Gained experience in object oriented programming using Objective-C and Cocoa toolkit.
- Worked effectively with the QA team to resolve any technical issues and bugs.

## **INTERNSHIPS**

Adobe Research
Research Intern

San Jose, CA

06/2017 - 08/2017

- Worked on applying 12 principles of animation to videos of human faces to achieve a stylized effect.
- Used face landmark detection algorithms to extract landmark coordinates over time and used Python to write image warping and signal processing algorithms to generate cartoonish stylized results.
- The results of the research were patented (See patents).

## **PUBLICATIONS**

**Interactive Modelling of Volumetric Musculoskeletal Anatomy.** 

Under review

Rinat Abdrashitov, Seungbae Bang, Alec Jacobson, David Levin, Karan Singh

Interactive exploration and refinement of facial expression using manifold learning.

**UIST 2020** 

Rinat Abdrashitov, Fanny Chevalier, Karan Singh

A System for Efficient 3D Printed Stop-Motion Face Animation.

SIGGRAPH 2020

Rinat Abdrashitov, Alec Jacobson, Karan Singh

Interactive Shape Modeling using a Skeleton-Mesh Co-Representation.

SIGGRAPH 2014

J. Andreas Bærentzen, Rinat Abdrashitov, Karan Singh.

Mosaic: Sketch-based interface for creating digital decorative mosaics.

SBIM 2014

Rinat Abdrashitov, Eric Yao, Emilie Guy, Karan Singh.

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: C++, C, Python

Numerics: MATLAB, NumPy, SciPy, Eigen

Graphics: OpenGL, GLSL

Machine Learning: PyTorch, Linear Algebra, Calculus, Convex Optimization

Software: Maya C++/Python API, Houdini, LibIGL

#### **PATENTS**

Reducing collision-based defects in motion-stylization of video content depicting closely spaced features (US Patent granted 2019)

Rinat Abdrashitov, Jose Ignacio Echevarria Vallespi, Jingwan Lu, Elya Shectman, Duygu Ceylan Aksit, David Simons